Are you the kind of person who hated school?
你是那种讨厌上学的人吗？
Or are you more like Michael Nicholson, who can't stop learning?
还是说，你更像迈克尔·尼科尔森无法停止学习？
He currently has 30 degrees including 22 master's and a doctorate!
他目前拥有30个学位，其中包括22个硕士学位和1个博士学位！
If you're also passionate about studying, you might be a philomath – a person who loves to learn and study.
如果你同样热衷于学习，那你可能就是一名“爱学者”——指热爱学习和钻研的人。
The word comes from Greek with 'phil' meaning 'a lover of' and 'math' meaning 'learning'.
这个词源于希腊语，“phil”意为“热爱……的人”，“math”则表示“学习”。
Humans are all philomaths to an extent – our brain is hardwired to be curious.
从某种程度上来说，人类都是热爱学习的人——我们的大脑天生就具备好奇心。
We want to learn and understand, partly to make sense of the world but also because of something called neoteny.
我们渴望学习和理解事物，一部分是为了认清世界的运行规律，另一部分则是源于一种名为“幼态延续”的现象。
This is a term that refers to the juvenile characteristics of some animals, including humans, being retained into adulthood.
这个术语指的是部分动物（包括人类）在成年后依然保留着幼年时期的特征。
One of these traits is neuroplasticity, which helps our brains stay flexible – this gives us the ability to learn throughout our lives.
其中一项特征就是神经可塑性，它能让我们的大脑保持灵活，让我们拥有终身学习的能力。
Many creatures which are genetically close to us, like primates, can't do this and only learn during their adolescence.
许多和我们基因相近的生物，比如灵长类动物，就不具备这种能力，它们的学习能力只存在于青春期。
But for every person who loves learning, there are plenty who can't stand it.
不过，有多少人热爱学习，就有多少人对学习深恶痛绝。
Lots of people remember their school days as being boring or even pointless.
很多人回忆起学生时代，都觉得那段时光枯燥乏味，甚至毫无意义。
Why is this?
这是为什么呢？
Educational anthropologists have suggested that if a concept or idea is too complex or dull, it becomes harder to link old and new ideas together.
教育人类学家指出，如果某个概念或知识点过于复杂、乏味，人们就很难将新旧知识串联起来。
If that's the case, we lose motivation and absorb less information.
一旦出现这种情况，我们就会失去学习动力，吸收的知识也会大打折扣。
This negative experience of education at school may lead to people avoiding learning opportunities in later life.
这种糟糕的校园学习经历，可能会导致人们在成年后刻意回避学习的机会。
So, don't let a bad educational experience prevent you learning something new as an adult.
所以，不要让一段糟糕的求学经历，阻碍你在成年后学习新事物的脚步。
Evolution has made us lifelong learners, so take advantage of your biology and discover your inner philomath.
进化让我们成为了终身学习者，所以请好好利用自身的生理优势，发掘内心深处那个热爱学习的自己吧。
Who knows what you could achieve?
谁知道你能取得怎样的成就呢？